VIKTORIIA BAHERIAN

FRONT-END ENGINEER

Hello, I'm Vika - a developer with a 6 years of experience in front-end. I've worked on all sorts of apps: from high-load products to small marketing landing pages. I strive to learn, love to share knowledge, and committed to what I do. Good at working on new technologies as well as supporting old-school codebase. Attentive to details, problem-solver and a great team player. Looking for a team of like-minded people.

CONTACT

+380999421955

Kyiv, Ukraine

INTERESTS

Hiking & travel

Snowboarding

Postcrossing

Bicycling

EDUCATION

Kyiv National Economic University

Computer science, bachelor

2013-2017

FILAB

Engineering management

January - March 2023

Engineering management course by Chris Kosyk & Dima Maleev

Projector - creative tech online instititute

Algorithms course

May - July 2023

LANGUAGES

English B2, Upper Intermediate

Ukrainian Native

SKILLS

- HTML/HTML5
- CSS/CSS3/SASS
- JavaScript
- React & ecosystem (Redux, react-router, you name it)
- · Tools: webpack, rollup
- Experience with RESTful APIs
- Storybook
- UI/UX design, responsive design and cross-browser development
- Testing with Jest, React Testing Library, or Enzyme.
- · Version control with GitHub
- · Performance optimization
- Scrum/Agile/Kanban

.....

EXPERIENCE

Team Lead

AirSlate, UserFlow team

December 2022 - May 2023

Led a team of front-end professionals to develop new features as well as support and improve existing parts of the app. Some of my duties were:

- Tech: code review, feature concept review, developing tech feature concepts and product improvement plans, writing tech and integration docs, feature development, rapid solving of incidents.
- Delivery: task decomposition & and estimation with a team, devising delivery plans for PI, release management, working closely with an ab-test system (starting user-based experiments and analyzing outcomes)
- Team: hiring, mentoring, creating personal growth plans for teammates, 1-2-1s, performance review, across-team communication

Front-end engineer

AirSlate, UserFlow & TrueEdit teams

February 2019 - December 2022

2016 - 2019

As a part of the UserFlow team worked on the user account page, the login process, and various modules, which were designed to accommodate users' needs. Developed and delivered features independently as well as part of a team. Especially proud of:

- reducing the mobile version in size by twice via code refactoring and optimization
- increasing code test coverage, reducing tech debt, and improving security

Front-end engineer

WINNLAB

As a part of the WINNLAB team, I worked on developing various marketing landing pages and platforms. Most of them included animations, interactive graphs, and adaptations to different screen types and sizes. As it were advertising materials I had a lot of experience with the best SEO principles and optimizations needed for search engines.